Guide to the 1968 Revisited Exhibition Collection MC 132
New York University Archives
The 1968 Revisited Exhibition Collection
1993
MC 132
New York University Archives
1.25 linear feet (3 boxes)
The 1968 Revisited Exhibition Collection reflects the work presented by the New York University Archives in October 1993. The exhibit touches on topics, events and people of the late 1960s at NYU. Material used in the exhibit comes from the collections within the University Archives. A digital version of the exhibit was later created by Amy Surak, a former employee of the University Archives. This digital exhibit displays many of the materials found in the physical exhibition.
New York University. University Archives.
History of the 1968 Revisted Exhibition
1968 Revisited was an exhibit presented by the New York University Archives in October 1993. The exhibit highlights the radicalism that was prevalent at NYU during the late 1960s. The exhibit was divided into a timeline portion and a Who’s Who section. The timeline documents the events that occurred both worldwide and at NYU between the years 1965-1971. The Who’s Who portion covers different individuals and student organizations that were prominent during this time of strikes and upheaval. The majority of the information from both the timeline and the Who’s Who section focuses on the events and actions of different individuals and groups in 1968. Topics discussed in the exhibit include the Vietnam War, Nixon’s election, the Black Panthers, among many other controversial events and protests. The exhibit remembers groups such as the Students for a Democratic Society and the Transcendental Students who performed numerous sit-ins, strikes and other actions against the University administration. Dates are included before and after 1968 allowing the viewer to get a full understanding of the causes and effects of the events that happened in 1968. A website created by Amy Surak, containing a digital version of the exhibit, is available through the New York University Archives website.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into three series.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of materials displayed during the exhibit in 1993. Most of the material has been mounted on panels that were used for the exhibit. The newspaper articles, photographs, and many of the handouts are duplicates of original material that is held at the University Archives. The dates of the duplicated material range from 1965 to 1971, though the bulk of the material used in the exhibit is from 1968. The only original documents included in this collection are located in the folders titled: SDS Pamphlets, Rampart Magazine, and Rampart Magazine Cover, all located in Box 2. Student groups such as the Students for a Democratic Society (SDS), Transcendental Students, the Peace and Freedom Party, and the Youth International Party (YIPPIE!) were vocal participants in the events that occurred at NYU during this time. The material in this collection reflects the actions of these student groups and documents significant events that occurred during this time. Box 3 consists of photocopied material of the exhibit panels and Washington Square Journal articles.
Conditions Governing Access
The audiovisual materials in this collection have not been converted to a digital format. Patrons should contact the University Archives for access.
Hatchett, John F.; Hester, James M., 1924-; Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968; King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1929-1968; Nixon, Richard M., (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994; Exhibitions.; New York University |x Students.; New York University. Loeb Student Center; Students for a Democratic Society (U.S.). New York Region; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Protest movements--United States.
- Series I:Timeline, 1993
  - University Complicity with the War Effort, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Tet Offensive, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - President Johnson Renounces Bid for Re-Election, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Students Protest Against DOW Chemical, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - NYU Adopts Minority Recruitment Policy, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Martin Luther King Jr is Assassinated, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Columbia University Strike, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Paris Students Protest, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Robert Kennedy Assassinated, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Anti-War Protestos and Police Battle in Chicago, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Hatchett Controversy, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Nixon Protests, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Hatchett Strike, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1968 Election, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Vote in the Streets, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Nixon Defeats Humphrey, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Chi-Reston Incident, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Open Admission Rally, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Freak-In", 1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Panther 21, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Radicals Raid ROTC Offices, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "The Decade's Change" Article, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Rally for Panther 21, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - NYU Reacts, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Attica Prison Rebellion, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Timeline Labels, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Copies of Panels from Exhibit, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Photos from Exhibit, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Tet Offensive Panel, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1968 French Revolution Panel, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Series II: Who's who, 1967-1993
  - Who's Who Labels, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Black Panthers, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Committee to End the War in Vietnam, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Peace and Freedom Party, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - President James Hester, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Students for a Democratic Society (SDS), 1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - SDS Pamphlets, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Materials from SDS, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Transcendental Students, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - YIPPIE! (Youth International Party), 1993 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Eldridge Cleaver, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - The Garrison Society, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - University Worker Student Coalition, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - SDS Panels, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Black Allied Student Association, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Series III: Additional Material, 1969-1993
  - Ramparts Magazine, July 1969 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Ramparts Magazine Cover, November 1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Poetry Panal, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1968 Revisted: Bobst Library Exhibit Opening Unedited Version VHS, October 14, 1993 (Box 2)
  - 1968 Revisted: Bobst Library Exhibit Opening Edited Version VHS, October 14, 1993 (Box 2)
  - 1968 Revisted Cassette Tape, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Photocopies, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Photocopies, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Photocopies, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Photocopies, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Washington Square Journal Panels, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Exhibit Panels, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Washington Square Journal Photocopies, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Washington Square Journal Photocopies, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Washington Square Journal Photocopies, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Washington Square Journal Photocopies, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Washington Square Journal Photocopies, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)